Now let's talk about the use of honey in natural facial cleansers.
Honey is a natural antiseptic, and research has also found it to be a natural antibacterial agent.
Both of these properties help to fight acne.
As we talked about before, acne is created or caused by bacteria.
And honey is also used in open wounds.
Many people use this instead of using the commercial creams because of the antiseptic and antibacterial properties.
Honey can be moisturizing, soothing, and softening, and the sugar in honey also helps to gently ex-foliate to remove some of the dead skin.
Honey can be an allergen to some people but you can reduced this allergic reaction by buying organic, local honey.
The reason for this is that you are already used to the local pollens in the air, and the bees use those to create the honey.
Now let's talk about the use of milk in facial cleansers.
Milk can be very softening and soothing.
It's also very hydrating.
The vitamins A and D that can be found in milk are good for you complexion.
In fact, Cleopatra was known to soak in milk baths to help her complexion.
Instead of using cows milk, you can use soy milk as well.
Soy milk is rich in vitamins and proteins that are known to stimulate circulation.
Soy milk also has the natural estrogens that can be very, very good for your complexion.
Milk can be an allergen for some people, so make sure that you feel comfortable using milk in your recipes.